(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T06:18:03.645627",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はーい、というわけで
Hi, so...
みんな見えてますか？
can everyone see me?
今日は紫シオン3周年ということで
Today marks Murasaki Shion's 3rd anniversary,
みんな、見えてる？
can you all see me?
今日は生誕祭ライブに来てくれてありがとう！いぇーい！
Thank you for coming to my birthday live! Yay!
はーい、みなさんありがとうございました。
Right, everyone, thank you so much.
ほんとにね、あの、今日は誕生日を祝っていただけて最高の誕生日になった
Really, um, having you celebrate my birthday made it the best birthday ever.
本当に嬉しかった。みんなありがとう！
I'm so happy. Thank you everyone!
見てくれたみんなもありがとう！
Thank you to everyone who watched too!
暗い方ばっか見てないで
Don't just keep looking at the dark side,
ウラパッパッパパラリラ踊れよ
Ura-pa-pa-pa-paralira, dance!
魔界学校の優等生
An honor student of the demon world school,
華やかな我が魔力讃えよ
Praise my gorgeous magical power!
イナイイナイばぁでこっち向いて
With a peek-a-boo, turn over here
芳かな未来を咲かせよ
Let's make a brilliant future bloom
次第愛だって高まって
Gradually, love builds up higher
溜まったmp放て黒魔術
Unleash the stored MP with black magic!
定の刻に集えよ
Gather at the appointed hour,
闇に震えケルベロス
Cerberus, trembling in the darkness!
切に響く言葉は
The words echoing so earnestly are
ブチギレ発狂パラダイス
A furious, going-crazy paradise!
キラリ ココロ オクソコ まで 届け
Reach deep down into my sparkling heart
これからも 私 の 元 で
From now on, by my side
不思議な力打ち放って
Unleashing mysterious powers,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making the whole world smile too!
ウラパッパ パッパ パラリラ 歌えば
If we sing Ura-pa-pa pa-pa paralira,
一生一緒だよね？
We'll be together forever, right?
暗いもんだか走ってないで
Don't run around gloomy and downcast,
黙った身体さらば踊れよ
Leave your silent body behind and dance!
視界外目逸らさないで
Don't look away out of your field of view,
今はただ離れてかないで
Right now, just don't leave my side!
いやいや待ってあっち向いて
No way, wait, look over there
今はまだ心の準備を
Right now, I'm still preparing my heart
期待遮って固まって
Interrupting expectations, freezing up
ウラパッパッパ動け黒魔術
Ura-pa-pa-pa, move, black magic!
我に続け今宵の
Follow me tonight, to...
闇を破れ救世主よ
Break the darkness, savior!
討つべき者その名は
The name of the one to defeat is
眠りの発作パラダイス
Sleep-attack paradise!
キラリ ココロ オクソコ まで 届け
Reach deep down into my sparkling heart
白黒つけてあげるから
Because I'll settle things for you
不思議な力振りかざして
Brandishing mysterious power,
みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
Making everyone smile together!
ウラパッパ パッパ パラリラ 歌えば
If we sing Ura-pa-pa pa-pa paralira,
一生一緒かもね？
We might be together forever?
ひらりひらりと紫に染まって
Fluttering, fluttering, dyed in purple,
これからのあなたの下で
From now on, under your guidance
奇跡の呪文解き放って
Unleashing a miraculous spell
咲かせる笑顔の花を
Making the flower of smiles bloom!
キラリ ココロ オクソコ まで 届け
Reach deep down into my sparkling heart
これからも変わらないままで
Remaining unchanged from now on as well
不思議な力ほら宿って
Look, a mysterious power resides within
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making the world smile too!
ウラパッパ パッパ パラリラ 歌えば
If we sing Ura-pa-pa pa-pa paralira,
一生一緒だよね？
We'll be together forever, right?
絶対一緒だよね？
Definitely together forever, right?
はーい！というわけで、紫シオン4周年記念イェーイ！
Hi! And so, Murasaki Shion 4th Anniversary, yay!
このね、出てると思うんですけど画面の端に、どっち？こっちかな？こっちだ！
This is showing up on the edge of the screen, which side? Is it this side? It's this side!
出てる通りハッシュタグ紫シオン4周年記念でぜひいっぱいツイートしてください！スクショもねいっぱい撮ってね！
As shown, please tweet a lot with the hashtag Murasaki Shion 4th Anniversary! Take lots of screenshots too!
はーい、なんと4周年らしいです。
Hii, somehow it's already the 4th anniversary.
ねぇ、びっくりだよね！だって、5年目に突入しちゃうわけでしょ。
Right, isn't it surprising? Because we're already entering the 5th year.
5年ってさ、普通に考えてやばいよね。なんかこう、5年ってなんかちょっと、5でキリが言いから
5 years, normally thinking, is crazy. Like, 5 years feels like... 5 is a clean number
ま、まだ4年、4年なんですけど。
Well, it's still 4 years, 4 years though.
いやすごい、本当に。長いようで短かった気がする。
Man, it's amazing, really. It feels like it was long yet short.
ね、サムネもね、見て、後ろにあるんだけどさ、ちょっと遠いな。遠いけど、後ろにある通りめちゃめちゃかわいいでしょ！ね、このサムネに写ってる通りですね、なんと
Right, look at the thumbnail too, it's behind me, though it's a bit far. It's far, but just like it is behind me, it's super cute! Right, exactly as shown in this thumbnail, somehow...
ゲストが3人来てくれてまーす！
three guests have come!
楽しみだね！
I'm looking forward to it!
おっ、さっそくゲストの1人目が来てるみたい。
Oh, looks like the first guest has arrived right away.
うぇー、かわいい！見て！
Ugh, so cute! Look!
ねこちゃん。ちょっとねこちゃん。
It's a cat. Hey, cat...
今日からママになります。
Starting today, I'm going to be its mama.
ね、みんなこれ重大発表です、これ。
Hey everyone, this is a major announcement.
ママになりました。嘘です。
I became a mama. Just kidding.
ね、ほら。ねこちゃん、ねこちゃん殴って、延長しちゃ。
Hey, look. Cat, cat, punch it and extend it.
かわいい！マジでかわいいこいつ！
So cute! This little guy is seriously cute!
みんなのだよ、でも。
It belongs to everyone, though.
やばい！リスナー抱いてるこれ。
Oh no! It's holding a listener, this.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
リスナーバイバーイ！かわいい、しおっこう。
Listener, bye-bye! So cute, Shiokko.
マジでかわいい。ね、ステージのね、ここにもちょこんとね。
Seriously cute. Hey, right here on the stage too, it's sitting right here.
ね、両端にいるんだよ、これ。
Hey, they're on both ends, you know.
ここ、ここ、ここ、ここ！
Right here, right here, right here!
かわいい！このステージめっちゃきれいだなマジで。プラネタリウムみたい。
Cute! This stage is seriously so pretty. It's like a planetarium.
はい！というわけでね、この後もまだまだわたくしここはたくさん続くので、ぜひ楽しんでください！
Yes! So, there are still plenty of segments coming up after this, so please enjoy them!
なんと！そして最後に！
And what's more, finally!
重大告知もあります！最後までちゃんと見て。
There's also a major announcement! Make sure to watch all the way to the end.
ちゃんと、ちゃんと、ずっと1秒たりとも目を離さず見てください！
Make sure, make sure, don't take your eyes off it for even a single second!
次はゲストが来てます。もう。
Next up, a guest has arrived. Already.
というわけで、いこー！
So, let's go!
やんらりぱっぱらぱっぱぱらぱ
Yalilapa-palapapa-palapa
純粋が仇になる世界で
In a world where pureness backfires,
やんらりぱっぱらぱっぱぱらぱ
Yalilapa-palapapa-palapa
また来週も戦えるかな
I wonder if I can fight again next week.
可愛い衣装まとって
Dressed in cute outfits,
決めポーズで光って
Shining in striking poses,
ピュアな想い魔法に変えて
Turning pure feelings into magic,
みんなの平和願って
Wishing for everyone's peace,
邪悪に立ち向かって
Standing up against evil,
それを匿名はディスった
While anonymous people dissed it.
「本当は〇〇なんですか？」
"Aren't you really XXX?"
「ぶっちゃけ〇〇なんですか？」
"Honestly, aren't you XXX?"
自分があそう思うからみんな〇〇であってほしいんだろ
Because you think that way yourselves, you want everyone to be XXX too, right?
そんな手垢のついたよくある風評で
With those worn-out, common rumors
錆びつくだけ魔法のステッキ
My magic wand just rusts away.
知らん知らん
I don't know, I don't know!
はあ正直もうやめたい
Ha, honestly I just want to quit
魔法少女をやめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl
誰が敵か味方かわからないし
I never know who's friend or foe,
「陰険」で「強欲」で「滑稼」で「外道」で
"Devious", "greedy", "parasitic", "heretical" —
魔法がとけるチョコみたいに
My magic melts away like chocolate.
やんらりぱっぱらぱっぱぱらぱ
Yalilapa-palapapa-palapa
純粋が仇になる世界で
In a world where pureness backfires,
はあ正直もうやめたい
Ha, honestly I just want to quit
魔法少女をやめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl
もう好きな人だけ守っていたい
I just want to keep the people I love safe.
やだんだんディダンだんだんディダン
Ya dan-dan-di-dan-dan-dan-di-dan
やだんだんディダンだんだんディダンディダン
だんだん身勝手になる
Becoming increasingly selfish,
魔力が煮え立つ
My magical power boils over.
不満で調和したポーションがプリン
The potion harmonized with dissatisfaction is pudding.
「お前ら〇〇なんですか？」
"You guys, are you XXX?"
「性根が〇〇なんですか？」
"Is your nature XXX?"
怒りに任せ脳内で〇〇しちゃうんでしょう
Yielding to anger, you probably XXX in your head, right?
やり取りはナンセンス 気にやんでもスルーです
Back-and-forth is nonsense, I'll just ignore it even if I care.
光失ったブローチ
The brooch that lost its light
腐る腐る
Rots and rots away.
はあ正直もうやめたい
Ha, honestly I just want to quit
魔法少女をやめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl
視聴者の期待に応える度に
Every time I meet the audience's expectations,
「完璧」で「超人」で「清廉」で「潔白」で
"Perfect", "superhuman", "pure", "innocent" —
嘘で固めたチョコみたいに
Wrapped in lies like chocolate.
やんらりぱっぱらぱっぱぱらぱ
Yalilapa-palapapa-palapa
甘い味が闇付きでしょ
The sweet taste is addictive, right?
はあ正直もうやめたい
Ha, honestly I just want to quit
魔法少女をやめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl
「やめないで」って言われんの期待してない？
Aren't you hoping someone will say "Don't quit"?
ファンのお金も心配してることも...
And you're worried about the fans' money too...
すべて目を塞いでしまったの
You've closed your eyes to it all.
はあ正直もうやめたい
Ha, honestly I just want to quit
魔法少女をやめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl.
誰が敵か味方かわからないし
I never know who's friend or foe,
「陰険」で「強欲」で「滑稼」で「外道」で
"Devious", "greedy", "parasitic", "heretical" —
魔法で最低な人を消そう
Let's erase the worst people with magic.
はあ正直もうやめたい
Ha, honestly I just want to quit
魔法少女をやめたい
I want to quit being a magical girl
自分ごと消えちゃってさようならなら
If I disappear along with it all, goodbye.
やんらりぱっぱらぱっぱぱらぱ
Yalilapa-palapapa-palapa
純粋が仇になる世界で
In a world where pureness backfires,
やんらりぱっぱらぱっぱぱらぱ
Yalilapa-palapapa-palapa
また来週も見してくれるかな
I wonder if you'll watch me again next week.
はい、というわけで魔法少女とチョコレートでした！はーい！はーい！
Yes, so that was "Mahou Shoujo to Chocolate"! Yay! Yay!
あのさあ、
Um, you know...
はい。
Yes.
あのさあ
Um, you know
何ですか？
What is it?
「あのさあ」から始まるMC、
An MC that starts with "Um, you know..."
なんですか？
What is it?
ふたりでさ、はい。
The two of us, yeah.
配信するのいつぶりか知ってる？
Do you know how long it's been since we streamed together?
配信っていうか、いつぶり
Stream... I mean, how long...
こうやって喋ってるの。
has it been since we talked like this?
いつぶりなんですか？
How long has it been?
1年ぶりらしいよ。
Apparently it's been a year.
えーーー！い、い、1年ぶりー！
Eeh?! I-I-It's been a year!
びっくりだよね。
That's surprising.
え、や、ヤバイね。普通にびっくり。
E-Y-Yeah, that's crazy. Seriously surprising.
え、そりゃだって、あくシオちゃん、
I mean, AquaShion,
あくシオちゃんだよ。
AquaShion, you know!
うわ、懐かしいな。
Wow, how nostalgic.
あくシオちゃんのあの名シーン。
That legendary AquaShion scene.
名シーンって何？名シーンって、
What legendary scene? Legendary scene?
全然覚えてないな。1番の名シーンよ。
I totally don't remember. The number one legendary scene!
いや、全然覚えてないな。もう1年経つし、記憶が
No, I totally don't remember. It's been a year, and my memory...
あ、TISGでしょ？
Ah, "I'm number two", right?
ん？なんですか、それは？
Hmm? What is that?
な、なんですか、それは？まあ、それは一旦置いときましょう。
Wha- what is that? Well, let's put that aside for now.
いやいやいや、ちょっと待って。
No, no, no, wait a second.
やめときましょう。私分からないので。
Let's drop it, since I don't know.
でもさあ、さっき言ってたじゃん。
But hey, you just said it earlier!
公式になったって、あれ。
That it became official.
公式っていうか、そうね、ガオ先生の、あのコミケのグッズに、
Official, I mean, right, Gao-sensei's, um, Comic Market merch...
あたしがが、なんか出てましたよね。あたし全然わからないんですけど。
featured... me? I totally don't know anything about it, though.
あ、何のことかわからないですけど。
Ah, I don't know what you're talking about.
あなたは蟹になったんだよ。
You became a crab.
蟹になった！
I became a crab?!
なりたくてなったわけじゃないんだよ。
I didn't become one because I wanted to!
なれたんだよ、やっと。
You finally became one, though.
いやだから、あの時、晒されたんだよね。あの1時間の配信の中で。
I mean, you got exposed back then. During that one-hour stream.
一番よかったあのシーンが。
That best scene ever.
忘れない。あの時のこと。
I'll never forget. That moment.
感動的なね。
It was so touching.
そう、歌の最中に。
Yeah, right in the middle of the song.
そうよ。
That's right.
いやぜひね、見たことない人はぜひ、あの、あくシオちゃんの3Dライブ見てみてください。感動するんで。
If you haven't seen it, please check out AquaShion's 3D live. It's so moving.
あのシーン
That scene...
しないわ。
I won't!
ギャグだよ。ギャグ。
It's a gag. A gag.
いやでもね、まあ、あの、この
But you know, um, this...
えっとな、魔法少女とチョコレート、この曲ね、あの、なんとう
"Magical Girl and Chocolate," this song, um, you know...
もうちょっと話し変えちゃうんですけど。
I'm going to change the topic a bit, though.
はい。
Yes?
なんでしょう？
What is it?
この曲ね、私思うことがあって。
About this song, I have something on my mind.
なんかちょっとさ、この曲、なんか誰かと
It's like, this song, with someone...
しゅんちゃん歌ってな...
Shion-chan sang...
え、初めて歌ったよ。
Eh, I sang it for the first time!
いやいや、ちょっと待って、私ね、この日のライブのために、一生懸命聞いて覚えて、あくあちゃんののために
No, no, wait, I worked really hard listening and learning it for this live, for Aqua-chan's sake...
ちょっと待って。結構前に歌ってみた動画で、
Wait a minute. A while ago, in a cover song video,
あの、2時3時の星川さんと歌ってた記憶があるんですけど。
I remember singing it with Nijisanji's Hoshikawa-san.
いや！
No!
ちょっとないよ、そんなの。
There's no such thing!
いや、私の記憶が正しければ、あの、ちゃんと歌いたくて、あくあちゃんのために覚えて、あくあちゃんと初めて今ここで歌ったよ。
If my memory is right, I wanted to sing it properly, learned it for Aqua, and this is the first time I sang it here with Aqua!
いや、ちなみにパートも、なんか、星川のパートは私が
By the way, the parts too... Hoshikawa's part, I...
歌わされてて、あの、星川の代わりみたいになってる気がするんだけど。
was made to sing, and it feels like I'm just acting as Hoshikawa's replacement.
いや、なわけないじゃん！あくあちゃんしかいないよ。
No way! There's only Aqua!
あくあちゃんのために歌詞分けも考えて一生懸命も、ここあくって歌ったほうがいいとか、
For Aqua's sake, I thought about the lyric distribution, worked hard, thinking it's better to sing "Coco Aqua" or something...
もっと星川って書いてある部分をあくあって直して、そんなのいいよ。
and replacing "Hoshikawa" with "Aqua"... No way!
なわけないじゃん、そんなわけ。
No way, that's impossible.
いや私、星川の代わりなんですね、しょせん。しょせん代わりものなんですね。あくあしかいないよ。
I'm just a replacement for Hoshikawa, after all. Just a substitute. There's only Aqua.
誰でもいいんだ。あくあしかいないよって。
Anyone is fine, huh? "There's only Aqua."
私にはあくあしかいないよ！
For me, there's only Aqua!
言ったね？
You said it?
言った、言った、言った。
I said it, I said it.
絶対だからね。
Remember, for sure.
じゃあ私が後でYouTube見て、あの、星川と歌ってる動画あったら、マジで、あの、削除申請めっちゃするからね。
Then later, if I check YouTube and find a video of you singing with Hoshikawa, I'll seriously submit a ton of deletion requests!
星川さんの非公開にしてもらってね、いったん。この後。
Make Hoshikawa-san's private first. After this.
いやね、でもね、あれで可愛かったですよ。
Well, you know, but that was cute though.
あ、聞いてくれたんだ。
Ah, you listened to it.
歌ってないけど。えー、もうYouTubeに上がってる気がするけど、歌ってないけど聞いてくれたんだね。
I didn't sing it, though. Eh, I feel like it's already on YouTube, but even though I didn't sing it, you listened to it.
聞きました。
I listened.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
いや、すごいよかった。ね、今回ね、一緒に歌えて、本当に良かったよ。
It was really great. You know, singing together this time was truly wonderful.
うん、ありがとう。本当に。
Yeah, thank you so much.
あとね、あのミニライブの赤紫色の、マジでよかった。
Also, that mini-live's purplish-pink palette was really great.
紫色のパレットね？
The purple palette, right?
なんですか、紫色のパレットって何の曲？
What is that? What song is "purple palette"?
あのお、あの、
Um, well...
なんか、紫、紫色パレットっていうんですか？
Is it called something like a purple palette?
それ、紫色パレットって言うんだよ。
It's called the purple palette.
あれいいよね、あれ。
That's really nice, isn't it?
あれメインチョコクレイジー色は？
What about the main choco-crazy color?
あれは、あれは、あっ、あくあちゃんのオリ曲でしょ？
That's Aqua-chan's original song, right?
ねぇ、もっとのやつでしょ？
Hey, that's "Neemotto", right?
そう、ねぇもっとのやつ。あれはメジャーなアクアイロ。
Right, "Neemotto". That's the major Aquayiro.
じゅるぱ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ら、ら、る、る、る、る、るのやつは？
What about the "jurupa po po po..." one?
あ、それはアクアイロ。
Ah, that's Aquayiro.
ぐちゃぐちゃになってんじゃん。
It's all a total mess!
いや、すごい可愛かったよ。
No, it was super cute!
いや、ありがとう。
Yeah, thank you.
これからね、どんどんたぶんゲストの人も出るのかな？
I wonder if more guests will appear from now on?
出る、出る。
They will, they will.
ちょっと楽しみですね。
I'm looking forward to it.
ちょっと見てますよ。
I'll be watching.
君だけだよ。
Just you.
適当なこと言ってんじゃねえよ。
Don't say random things!
帰りな。
Go home.
じゃあね、じゃあね、あくあちゃん。
See ya, Aqua-chan.
え？ちょっと待って、違う、違う、違う、違う、待って、あなたが帰ったらどうするのここ！
Wait, what are we gonna do if you go home?!
え？あ、私かに、私、私かに…ぶ、ぶ、ぶ、バイバイ。
Eh? Ah, I... bye-bye.
言って。
Say it.
あのね、私実は分かってるの
You know, I actually realized it,
ほら、君が言ったこと
see, what you said.
あまり考えたくなくて
I didn't want to think about it too much,
忘れてたんだけど
so I had forgotten about it.
盲目的に盲動的に妄想的に生きて
Living blindly, impulsively, delusionally,
衝動的な焦燥的な消極的なままじゃ駄目だったんだ
impulsive, impatient, and passive just won't do.
きっと人生最後の日を前に思うのだろう
Surely, when facing the last day of my life, I'll think
全部全部言い足りなくて惜しいけど
everything, everything is lacking and it's a shame, but
ああいつか人生最後の日
Ah, someday on the last day of my life,
君がいないことが
that you won't be there...
もっともっともっと
More, more, more...
あのね、空が青いのって どうやって伝えればいいんだろうね
You know, how should I convey that the sky is blue?
夜の雲が高いのって どうすれば君もわかるんだろう
How can I make you understand that the clouds are high at night?
言って。
Say it.
あのね、私実はわかってるの もう君が逝ったこと
You know, I actually understand that you've already passed away.
あのね、わからずやって言うんだろうね 忘れたいんだけど
You know, they'd call me stubborn for this, I want to forget, but
もっとちゃんと言ってよ 忘れないようにメモにしてよ
Say it to me more clearly, make a memo so I won't forget.
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's make plans to meet at the platform at 10 tomorrow.
牡丹は散っても花だよ
Peonies are flowers even when they scatter,
夏が去っても追慕は切だ
even when summer leaves, yearning is painful.
口に出して
Speak it out,
声に出して
give it your voice,
君が言って
you say it.
そして人生最後の日 君が見えるのなら
And on the last day of my life, if I can see you,
きっと人生最後の日も愛をうたうのだろう
surely even on the last day of my life I'll sing of love,
全部全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
because I'll say that everything wasn't in vain.
ああ、いつか人生最後の日
Ah, someday on the last day of my life,
君がいないことがまだ信じられないけど
even though I still can't believe that you won't be there...
もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、君が
More, more, more, more, more, more, more, you...
もっとちゃんと言って
Say it more clearly.
もっとちゃんと言ってよ 忘れないよ、メモにしとよ
Say it to me more clearly, don't forget, make a memo.
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしようよ
Let's meet at the platform at 10 tomorrow.
牡丹は散っても花だ
Peonies are flowers even when they scatter,
夏が去っても追憶は切だ
even when summer leaves, yearning is painful.
土に出して
Put it in the soil,
声に出して
give it voice,
君が言って
you say it.
そして人生最後の日 君が見えるのなら
And on the last day of my life, if I can see you,
きっと人生最後の日も愛をうたうのだろう
surely even on the last day of my life I'll sing of love,
全部全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
because I'll say that everything wasn't in vain.
ああ、いつか人生最後の日 君が…
Ah, someday on the last day of my life, you...
ないことが まだ信じられないけど
I still can't believe...
行ってでした…
And there it was...
むちゃめちゃね、映像が綺麗だったの。見てました？みんな。見れてた？
The visuals were seriously so gorgeous. Did you all see it? Could you see it?
空がね、青いのってどうやって伝えたらいいんだろうね？
How am I supposed to convey how blue the sky was?
でも青くて綺麗だった。マジで映像めっちゃ綺麗だった。
But it was so blue and pretty. Seriously, the visuals were gorgeous.
はい、行ってはね、シオンね、思い出の、ちょっと思い出のさ、曲で、あの、本家のね、PVもめっちゃあの、素敵なんでみんな聴いてみてください！
Yeah, and that song is a special memory of mine... The original MV is super wonderful too, so everyone go listen to it!
次は……なんだろうな？なんだろうな？次は……コラボでーす！どうぞ！
Next is... I wonder what? I wonder what? Next is... a collaboration! Here you go!
愛のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Spoiler alert, love's a breakup,
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Life's spoiler alert, it looks like death.
なにそれ意味深で かっこいいじゃん
What's with that deep and cool meaning?
それっぽい単語集で 踊ってんだ
Dancing around with a collection of words like that.
っぽいジャン っぽいジャン
So-ish, so-ish,
神っぽいな
It's god-ish!
もういいぜ もういいぜ それもういいぜ もういいぜ 逆に興奮してきたな
That's enough, seriously enough, it's actually getting me excited!
景気いいけど 品性はTHE END
The economy's great, but decency is THE END.
うええい うええい Gott ist tot
Woah-oh, woah-oh, Gott ist tot.
神っぽいな
It's god-ish,
それ 卑俗
that vulgarity.
神っぽいな
It's god-ish,
それ My God
that "My God".
アイウォンチュー ウォンチュー IQが下がっていく感じ
I want you, want you, feeling my IQ drop.
邪心っぽいな
Wicked-ish,
それ 畢竟
that ultimately.
邪心っぽいな
Wicked-ish,
それ My God
that "My God".
アイヘイチュー ヘイチュー 害虫はどっち
I hate you, hate you, which one is the pest?
その髪型 その目 その口元
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth,
その香水 その服 そのメイク
that perfume, those clothes, that makeup.
アレっぽいな
That-ish,
それ 比況
that cowardice.
アレっぽいな
That-ish,
それ
that...
その名言 その意見 その批評
Those famous quotes, those opinions, those criticisms,
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
that charisma, that gag, that sense.
神っぽいな
It's god-ish,
それ 卑俗
that vulgarity.
っぽいな っぽいな ぽい あこがれちゃうわ！
-ish, -ish, -ish, I adore it!
神っぽいな
It's god-ish!
メタ思考する本質は悪意 人を小馬鹿にしたような作為
The essence of meta-thinking is malice, a contrived act making a mockery of people.
無為に生き延びるのは難しい 権力に呑まれて揺らぐ灯火
Surviving idly is hard, a flame flickering swallowed by power.
神を否定し神になり代わり 玉座で豹変する小者達
Denying God and taking His place, small fry changing colors on the throne.
批判に見せかけ自戒の祈り 「Do you know?」
A prayer of self-reflection disguised as criticism, "Do you know?"
何言ってんの？それ うざい
What are you even saying? That's annoying.
何言ってんの？それ
What are you even saying? That...
意味がよくわかんないし 眠っちうよ マジ
I don't really get the meaning, I'll fall asleep, seriously.
飽きっぽいんだ オーケー
Easily bored, okay?
みんな飽きっぽいんだ オーケー
Everyone gets easily bored, okay?
踊れるやつ頂戴頂戴ビーム…
Give me something I can dance to, beam...
キスっぽいな
Kiss-ish,
kiss-ish.
それキスっぽいな
That's kiss-ish,
キスっぽいな
kiss-ish.
逆にファンになってきちゃうじゃん
You're actually making me a fan.
ちっちゃいね
Tiny,
tiny.
その器ちっちゃいね
That vessel is tiny,
ちっちゃいね
tiny.
天才ゆえ孤独ですね 「かっけー…かっけー！！」
Lonely because of genius, "So cool... so cool!!"
Gott ist tot
神っぽいな
it's god-ish.
それ 卑俗
That vulgarity.
神っぽいな
It's god-ish.
それ My God
That "My God".
超健康 健康 言い張って くたばっていく感じ
Insisting you're super healthy, ending up dropping dead.
ヤケっぽいな
Desperate-ish,
それ 畢竟
that ultimately.
ヤケっぽいな
Desperate-ish,
それ My God
that "My God".
もう哀愁 哀愁 エピゴーンのヒール
Already sorrow, sorrow, the epigone's heel.
そのタイトル その絵 そのストーリー
That title, that picture, that story,
その音楽 その歌 そのメロディ
that music, that song, that melody.
アレっぽいな
That-ish,
それ 比況
that cowardice.
アレっぽいな
That-ish,
それ
that...
その名言 その意見 その批評
Those famous quotes, those opinions, those criticisms,
そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
that charisma, that gag, that sense.
神っぽいな
It's god-ish,
それ 卑俗
that vulgarity.
っぽいな っぽいな ぽい あこがれちゃうわ！
-ish, -ish, -ish, I adore it!
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Life's spoiler alert, it looks like death.
人生
Life.
4周年、おめでとうございます！
Happy 4th anniversary!
おすげえじゃん
Oh, that's awesome.
先輩だから
Because I'm your senior.
一応ね
Technically...
一応じゃねえわ
What do you mean "technically"?
お前何個離れとると思ってんねん
Do you know how many generations apart we are?
何期生だお前
What generation are you anyway?
え、だってろっ、ろっ、ろっ。ろっろでしょ？
Uh, well, gen 6, 6, 6—Gen 6, right?
こっちは2期なんだよ
I'm gen 2, you know.
うぇい、だから何、6の方が強いですけど
Well, so what? Gen 6 is stronger, though!
全く全然先輩よ
You're totally my junior!
いや大福岡では2期が一番強いから
Well, Gen 2 is the strongest in Fukuoka.
黙れ
Shut up!
髪っぽいなさ、先輩じゃん。だからデビュー前。そうね
You look like hair... I mean, you're my senior, right? So, before your debut. Right.
そう、だからさ、歌ってみた出すときさ、なんか被るみたいになったときさ、「あ、死んだわ、俺」ってなって
Yeah, so when I released a cover song and realized our concepts overlapped, I thought, "Ah, I'm dead."
え、マジでどうしようと思って。え、なってよ、なってよ。どうしようってだって気まずいって
I was like, "Seriously, what should I do?" And you were like, "What should I do?" It was so awkward!
いやわかるわかるわかる。で、あんま気にしないでおこうと思ってチャット送ったのがきっかけやね
I know, I know. So I sent you a chat hoping not to make a big deal out of it, and that was how it started.
あ、あの、連絡中しよんね
Ah, communicating with Shion-ne.
なんだお前。ちょっと、気まずいですね
What's with you? It's a bit awkward, huh?
いや、優しさやろ。優しさやろ
No, that's called being kind! That's being kind!
いや、でも今ではね、一緒に歌えるようになったね、ラプち
Well, but now we're able to sing together, Lap-chi.
たくさんなってね。あんな
So much. Like...
ハートちゅろハート
Heart-churo-heart
ハートちゅろ
Heart-churo
おたく
Otaku
逆だろ
That's the other way around!
いいじゃん。ハートになってるよ、音に。なってるじゃん
It's fine. It became a heart in the sound. It is!
いや気持ちでいいんだよこういうのは
Well, it's about the feeling with these things!
でお前写真いくつ？ 139だっけ
So how many photos do you have? 139 or something?
えでも角の角の方がでかいよ
But your horns are bigger, you know!
お前帽子取れよお前それ
Take off your hat, you!
ほら見て、並んだらほら見て
Look, when we line up, look!
いや同じぐらいじゃん
Well, they're about the same!
お前そんな生き出るほどでかくないぞそれは
You're not that much bigger, come on!
角取ったらお前こんなしかないよ
If you take off the horns, you've only got this much!
お前生きれるほどそんな変わってないからね
You haven't changed that much!
うるさいね君ね
You're noisy, you!
手名付けた、手名付けた、初めて言われたけど
Tamed, tamed, that's the first time I've been told that!
やめろ、並ぶな
Stop it, don't line up!
記念写真撮ろう。記念写真
Let's take a commemorative photo. Commemorative photo.
一応撮ろうよ、一応。一応ってなんだよ
Let's take one just in case. What do you mean "just in case"?
じゃあ正面写真撮ろう
Then let's take a front-facing photo.
わがはいたち正面写真？ 正面から
Us? Front-facing photo? From the front?
お前やば。いつでも見れるよこの絵
You're crazy. You can look at this drawing anytime!
もっとさ、4周年でさ、記念日じゃん今日は。うちらの記念ぴちゃんだから
Moreover, today's our 4th anniversary, it's our anniversary-pi!
なんでお前の記念日なんだよ。何の記念だよ
Why is it *your* anniversary? What anniversary is this?!
4周年も入れてよ一緒に。4周年ってことにしとけよ
Include the 4th anniversary together! Make it about the 4th anniversary!
とりあえず陰キャピースしよう、陰キャピース
For now, let's do the introverted peace sign, the introverted peace sign.
写真撮るときこれしかしないから。知らないんだよな最近流行っての
That's the only pose I do when taking photos. You don't know what's trending lately!
最近何流行ってんのポーズ
What poses are trending lately?
ギャルじゃない？ギャルって言ってたの
Isn't it gal? They were saying gal.
ギャル？ ギャルピースみたいな。あ、これ？
Gal? Like a gal peace. Ah, this?
ギャル？ ギャル。お前ぎこちな
Gal? Gal. You're so awkward!
はあお前、お前。ギャルになりきれてないから
Hey, you! You're not a gal yet!
いやいや、ギャル。超かわいい
No, no, gal. Super cute!
なんかギャルっぽいな。え、そうだな、そうだな。ギャルっぽいな、そうですね
Somehow it looks like a gal. Yeah, true, true. It looks like a gal, right?
しょうもな
How lame!
え、あれ、あれに、あれにする、エッチなやつ。上から撮ってもらう
Um, let's do that erotic one. Having it taken from above.
あ、いいじゃん。うわ、待って、ギャル、エッチ、みんな見ないで！
Ah, that's good. Woah, wait, gal, ecchi, everyone don't look!
もっと、もっと上から。ギャル！くねくねしろよお前もっと
More, more from above. Gal! Twist and turn more, you!
わがはいを見ろも、くねっ
Look at me, twist—
あ、エロい！エロい！
Ah, lewd! Lewd!
ケツ！エロい！ケツ！
Ass! Lewd! Ass!
ケツだよ、ケツ。髪の毛長すぎるぞお前
It's an ass! Your hair is way too long!
お前だけな、お前髪の毛長
Only you, your hair is long!
お前のチャンネルだからいいよ。なんでそんなこと言うねん
It's your channel so it's fine. Why are you saying that?!
4周年記念日にね、4周年記念バーン
On the 4th anniversary, 4th anniversary celebration!
うん、そう、第4回
Yeah, right, the 4th time.
いやでもなんかさ、3Dいいね！よかったこうやって隣で並べて
But you know, 3D is great! It's nice lining up next to each other like this.
そう、動き回れるからさ。殴れるよ、殴れるよもう
Yeah, because we can move around. We can punch, we can punch now!
うわ、お前、後輩いじめ、後輩いじめになる
Woah, you— bullying your junior, you're gonna look like a bully!
お盆かよお前。うつぼね、実物はこうやって
Are you a Bon festival lantern? Actually, in person—
実はこうやって裏でやってるのがバレる。違うよ、違うよ
Actually, people will find out we do this behind the scenes. No, that's not it!
ねえ、何してんの？ 決まなの？ わがはいは
Hey, what are you doing? Is it decided? I am—
違うよ、かわいいシオンちゃん
No, cute Shion-chan!
かわいいってこと？
You mean cute?
かわいいんじゃないの？ なんだお前
Aren't you cute? What's with you?
じゃあね、ありがとうね！
Well then, thank you!
まあ仕方ないから来てやったし
Well, since I had no choice, I came.
なんだお前 なんて全部上からなんだ？
What's with you? Why are you talking down to me?
言うこと全部上からなんだ どうしてた？
Everything you say is from up high. What's going on?
強いから
Because I'm strong.
上から？
From up high?
上から弱そう
You look weak from up high.
楽しかった どうしよう
That was fun. What should I do?
またね
See you later.
またね、やばい、お面
See you later. Oh no, my mask.
バイバイ、ありがとう
Bye-bye, thank you.
バイバイ
Bye-bye.
せーのっ
(One, two...)
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's no good.
もうそんなんじゃほら
Look, it won't work.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If words will ruin our relationship,
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた
then we won't need them, or so I thought.
それでてただけどあれ?なんかちがうかも
But wait, something's not right...
千里の道も一歩から 石のようにかたいそんな意思で
A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step.
塵も積もれば大和撫子? 死ぬ気で!いや死ぬ気で!
Little by little, I'll be your ideal girl. Give it all I've got!
ふわふわり ふわふわら あなたが名前を呼ぶ
Fluffy and fluttering, fluttery and fluffy, you call my name,
それだけで宙へ浮かぶ ふわふわる
and that alone makes me float to the sky.
ふわふわり ふわふわら あなたが笑っている
Fluttery and fluffy, fluffy and fluttering, you are smiling,
それだけで笑顔になる 神様ありがとう
and that alone brings a smile to my face. Thank you, God.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if our fateful encounter
巡り逢えたことが
was just a prank by fate,
しあわせなの
I feel so blessed.
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's no good.
もうそんなんじゃほら
Look, it won't work.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
そうそんなんじゃやだ
Yup, I don't want it like that.
ねえそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's not enough.
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
I just want you to look at me forever and ever.
私の中のあなたほど あなたの中の私の存在は
Even though I know that the presence I hold in your heart isn't nearly as big
まだまだ大きくないことも分かっているけれど
as the presence you hold in mine,
今この同じ瞬間 共有してる実感
at this very moment, we share this reality.
塵も積もれば大和撫子? 略してチリツモ大和撫子?
Little by little, a traditional Japanese woman!
くらくらり くらくらる あなたを見上げたら
Dizzy and spinning, spinning and dizzy, when I look up at you,
それだけでまぶしすぎて くらくらる
it's just so dazzling that I get dizzy.
くらくらり くらくらる あなたを思っている
Spinning and dizzy, dizzy and spinning, I'm thinking about you,
それだけでとけてしまう 神様ありがとう
and that alone makes me melt away. Thank you, God.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if our fateful encounter
巡り逢えたことが
was just a prank by fate,
しあわせなの
I feel so blessed.
コイスル 季節は 欲張り circulation
The season of love is a greedy circulation.
コイスル 気持ちは 欲張り circulation
The feelings of love are a greedy circulation.
コイスル 瞳は 欲張り circulation
The eyes of love are a greedy circulation.
コイスル 乙女は 欲張り circulation
The maiden in love is a greedy circulation.
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy and fluttering, fluttery and fluffy,
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
you call my name, and that alone makes me float to the sky.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Fluttery and fluffy, fluffy and fluttering,
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
you are smiling, and that alone brings a smile to my face.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God.
運命のいたずらでも
Even if our fateful encounter was just a prank by fate,
巡り逢えたことが
and our meeting was meant to be,
しあわせなの
I feel so blessed.
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that's no good.
もうそんなんじゃほら
Look, it won't work.
心は進化するよ もっともっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
そうそんなんじゃやだ
Yup, I don't want it like that.
ねえそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's not enough.
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
I just want you to look at me forever and ever.
くらーい！はーい、しよう！
Yay, let's do it!
今日は来てくれてありがとう！逢えて嬉しいよ！
Thank you for coming today! I'm so glad we could meet!
あたしも誘って…
Me too, inviting me...
来てくれて ありがとう、シオン先輩！
Thanks for coming, Shion-senpai!
4年半初めてあって コラボとか、
It's our first time doing a collab 4 and a half years!
歌ってみたとか上げたりしたよね。
Singing together and stuff, right?
うわ！ 時間が早く経ちますよね。
Time really flies, doesn't it?
初めての会話 まだ覚えています。
Do you still remember our first chat?
あの、会話 覚えてる！
Um, I remember our chat!
ぐら、だめでしょう！
Gura, no way!
やっと3Dだやったね！
We finally did 3D, huh?
実際にやってみてどうかな？ 印象とかある？
What was it like doing it for real? Any impressions?
うん、はい。
Um, yes.
シオン先輩は思ったより背が低いですよね。
Shion-senpai, your height is shorter than you thought, right?
ぐらだって小さいでしょ！ 3Dで見せて！
Gura, you're short too! Show us in 3D!
やだ、どうしよう。
No way, what should I do?
じゃあ、見せようかな先輩！ 見せて！
Let me show you, senpai!
ぐるって回ってぐるって。
Spinning around, spinning around!
可愛い！
Cute!
可愛い！ 尻尾が可愛い！
Your tail is cute!
おー、可愛い！
So cute!
ぐら写真撮ろよ！
Gura's photo shoot, yo!
うん、オッケーです！ やった、しおん！
Yep, okay! Let's do it, Shion!
次は、何する？
What's next?
ハート！ ハート！
Heart! Heart!
じゃあ、ラストは！
Okay, last one!
GO! GO! MANIAC
やばい 止まれない 止まらない
Oh no, I can't stop, I won't stop
昼に夜に朝にsinging so loud
During day, night, morning, I'm singing so loud
好きなことしてるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
I'm just doing the things I love, Girls Go Maniac
どんなメロディ こんなリリィック 探していきたいんだ もっともっと
I want to search for a melody and lyrics like that, more and more
みんな一緒にね Chance Chance 願いを Jump Jump 掲げて
Together with everyone, Chance Chance, let's show Jump Jump, our wishes
Fun Fun 想いを Shout Shout 伝えよう
Fun Fun, and say Shout Shout, how we feel
ミスったらリハっことにして、もっかい!
If we mess up, then we'll rehearse one more time!
ごめん 譲れない 譲れない
Sorry, I can't let it go, I won't let it go
縦・横・斜めswinging around
Down, across, and diagonally, I'm swinging around
好きな音出してるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
I'm just making the sound I love, Girls Go Maniac
どんなグルーヴ こんなリバーヴ 試していきたいんだ ずっとずっと
I want to try a groove like that, a reverb like this, forever and ever
息合わせてね Chase Chase 明日を Break Break 夢見て
Make us in tune with each other, Chase Chase, let's dream Break Break, of tomorrow
Faith Faith 強くで Shake Shake 盛り上がろう
Faith Faith, and swell up, Shake Shake, with strength
浴びたら忘れられないっしょ、嗣琴!
If we get showered in cheers, we won't be able to forget about it, right?!
ほんと現実実はマジカニラ小説より
Truly, reality is really stranger than fiction
ぼっちり暮しててもね ぶつかる出会い
No matter how much I space out, I bump into encounters
キュンってなったり グッときたりしてfunny
It's funny feeling my heart throbbing and leaping
何これってうめんだ? じゃあおぼれちゃおう
What? Is this destiny? Well then, let's lose ourselves
めいっぱい満喫しちゃおう
Let's satisfy ourselves the best we can
試験前も通常通り 引き裂けないfriendship
Before a test, as always, I can't tear apart our friendship
約束してないのに つい集まる放課後
Even though we didn't promise so, we unintentionally get together after school
どこだってメンバー揃った場所 即ステージ
No matter where the place the members are gathered is, it's instantly our stage
聞こえるよね? カウント
You can hear it, right? The count
当然笑顔だし 笑顔でね
Of course, I smile with a smile
春も夏も秋もstepping out, now
In spring, in summer, in fall, I'm stepping out, now
好きな人といるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
I'm just with my friends who I love, Girls Go Maniac
どんなドラミング こんなカッティング 受け入れてほしいんだ どうかどうか
I want you to take drumming like that, cutting like this, please oh please
目合わせてね Tune Tune 心も Amuse Amuse 重ねて
Make our eyes meet, Tune Tune, let's synch Amuse Amuse, our hearts, too
Loose Loose 気軽に Shoot Shoot 技磨こう
Loose Loose, and improve our technique, Shoot Shoot, comfortably
まだまだいけるはずでしょ、実際!
We should still be able to go on, right? Actually!
大人たちは言うけど 好きなことばかりしちゃ
Adults say so, they say we'll fail
ダメになるって言うけど そうかな!? どうかな!?
Doing only the things we love, but is that true?! What will we do??
ねえ好きなことに夢中になってる瞬間ってさ
Hey, the moment when I become absorbed in what I love doing
生きてるって感じだし…幸せだし…だからいいや…
It feels like I'm alive... I'm happy... So it's okay
つうかダメになるわけない。
So it means we won't fail.
やっぱ止まれない 止まらない
I knew it, I can't stop, I won't stop
昼に夜に朝にsinging so loud
During day, night, morning, I'm singing so loud
好きなことしてるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
I'm just doing the things I love, Girls Go Maniac
どんなメロディ こんなリリィック 探していきたいんだ もっともっと
I want to search for a melody and lyrics like that, more and more
みんな一緒にね Chance Chance 願いを Jump Jump 掲げて
Together with everyone, Chance Chance, let's show Jump Jump, our wishes
Fun Fun 想いを Shout Shout もっと
Fun Fun, and say Shout Shout more
Chance Chance 願いを Jump Jump 掲げて
Chance Chance, let's show Jump Jump, our wishes
Fun Fun 想いを Shout Shout 伝えよう
Fun Fun, and say Shout Shout, how we feel
気持ちいい ;) から yeah アンコール、もっかい!
Because it feels good, yeah, encore, one more time!
Oh my god ! No no music , no smile
Oh my god! No no music, no smile
Oh my god ! No no friends , no life
Oh my god! No no friends, no life
All right ! No no no stop going our way
All right! No no no stop going our way
We have a fabulous body , soul & love
We have a fabulous body, soul & love
Oh my god ! No no music , no smile
Oh my god! No no music, no smile
Oh my god ! No no friends , no life
Oh my god! No no friends, no life
All right ! No no no stop going our way
All right! No no no stop going our way
We have a fabulous body , soul & love
We have a fabulous body, soul & love
やばい 止まれない 止まらない
Oh no, I can't stop, I won't stop
昼に 夜に 朝に singing so loud
During day, night, and morning, singing so loud
好きなことしてるだけだよ Girls Go Maniac
Just doing what I love, Girls Go Maniac
あんなメロディ こんなリリック
A melody like that, a lyric like this
探していきたいんだ もっともっと
I want to search for more and more
みんな一緒にね chance chance 願いを
Together with everyone, chance chance, our wishes
jump jump 掲げて
Jump jump, let's raise them up
fun fun 想いを shout shout 伝えよう
Fun fun, our feelings, shout shout, let's convey them
お前の no music no my
Your no music, no my
お前の no when or light
Your no when or light
お前の no speed so baby hop our safely so
Your no speed, so baby hop, our safely so
お前の no music no my
Your no music, no my
お前の no when or light
Your no when or light
お前の no speed so baby hop our safely so
Your no speed, so baby hop, our safely so
お前の no music no my
Your no music, no my
お前の no when or light
Your no when or light
お前の no speed so baby hop our safely so
Your no speed, so baby hop, our safely so
お前の no music no my
Your no music, no my
お前の no when or light
Your no when or light
お前の no speed so baby hop our safely so
Your no speed, so baby hop, our safely so
とあるラブ...
To aru Love...
はーい、というわけで GO! GO! MANIAC でした！イェーイ！
So, that was "GO! GO! MANIAC"! Yay!
ねぇみんな、ずっと気になってた、えっ後ろになんか化け物いるじゃんって思ってたでしょ。
Hey everyone, you've been wondering, "Wait, are there monsters behind her?" right?
1体ずつ見てみよう。
Let's look at them one by one.
まずこいつね。こいつ頑張ってね、絶対それ弾けないじゃんみたいな手の短さで頑張ってね、どうやって弾いてたんでしょうか。
First, this guy. He tried so hard with those short arms, thinking, "There's no way he can play that!" I wonder how he played it.
どうやって弾いてたんでしょうか彼は。頑張って弾いてくれてました。かわいいね。
How on earth did he play it? He worked hard to play for us. So cute.
踏み、踏みたい。踏みたいかわいいさしてるね。
I want to step, step on him. He looks so cute you just want to step on him.
次ね、こいつね。
Next, this guy.
ねぇ君、どうやって叩いてたの？叩けるのそれ？
Hey you, how were you drumming? Can you even play that?
あっ叩けるね、かわいいね。肉球みたいな肉球あるじゃん、かわいいね。
Ah you can play, how cute. You've got paw-like paws, so cute.
皆さんこれさ、なんか頑張ってる時さ、こうてくてくってしながらさ頑張ってたじゃん。この顔がいいよね、頑張ってますみたいな。ね、頑張ってますね。
Everyone, when they were working hard, they were walking all cute while playing. That face is great, like "I'm doing my best." Yeah, they're working hard.
かわいい、偉いね。次ね。
So cute, good job. Next.
これ、これ何て言うんだっけ？
What do you call this again?
ドラムだ、ドラム思い出したドラムだ。かわいい。
Drums, I remembered, it's drums. Cute.
で、こいつね、こいつベース。こいつもうね、あのキーボードの人と一緒、一緒でどうやって弾いててんみたいな。
And this guy, this guy's bass. This guy too, just like the keyboard guy, like how on earth is he playing?
ほんま、こんなちっちゃな手でどうやって弾いてるのこれ。
Seriously, how is he playing with hands this tiny?
あー頑張って、あー頑張ってたの、そうやって、あーそうやって頑張ってたの。絶対弾けてませんと。
Ah, he worked hard... Ah, so that's how he worked hard. Definitely not playing a single note.
めっちゃかわいいね、こうやって頑張ってたんだよ。
Super cute, he was working so hard like that.
いやー、GO! GO! MANIACね、あの、本当にめちゃめちゃ頑張って覚えたんだけど、歌を、歌を。そもそも歌をめっちゃ頑張って覚えたの。
Man, "GO! GO! MANIAC"... I really worked super hard to memorize it, the vocals. First of all, I worked so hard just to learn the singing.
どこが一番大変だったかっていうと、あの最後のドラムのパートね。ドラムじゃねえわ、なんだ？
Where was the hardest part? That would be the last drum part... wait, not drums, what is it?
ドラムじゃない、あの、なんだっけ？ 英語の「てゅるんてゅるんてゅるんてゅるん」ってところ、めちゃめちゃ頑張って覚えた。どうやって覚えたかっていうと、カタカナで歌詞に書いて、ね、聞こえる、こうやって聞こえるなっていうのを歌詞に書いて頑張って覚えたんだよ。めっちゃ大変だったんだから。
Not drums, um, what was it? The English "turun-turun-turun" part, I worked so super hard to memorize. How did I memorize it? I wrote the lyrics in katakana, writing down how it sounded to me, and worked hard to learn it. It was so tough.
あとね、ダンスもね、見た？みんなダンスも。頑張っててさ。ダンスも覚えるの大変だったんだからね。
And also, the dance too, did you see? Everyone, the dancing too. I worked hard. Learning the choreography was really tough too.
あのね、振り付けを考えてもらったんだけど、サビメロのね、あの、こうやって足を、こうやって足をさ、こうやってちこんて、こうやってやるところがね、可愛かったね。可愛い振り付けだったって。
You see, they came up with the choreography for me, and in the chorus melody, you know, moving your legs like this, tapping them down like that—that part was so cute. It was such a cute choreography.
やん、可愛くってさ、みんな。惚れちゃ、惚れられたら困っちゃう。
Aww, it's so cute, everyone. If you fall in love with me, I'll be in trouble.
ねえ、というわけで GO! GO! MANIAC でした！可愛い曲だよね。しかもね、ちょっと前に KEI-ON を見始めて、まだね、あの、まだね、全部見れてないんだけど、ちょっと長くて、長くて最近ちょっとね、見れてないんだけど、めちゃいいよね、けいおんね。
Anyway, that was "GO! GO! MANIAC"! Such a cute song. Also, I started watching K-ON! a little while ago, and I haven't finished watching all of it yet—it's a bit long, so lately I haven't been able to watch much, but K-ON! is so good.
そう、けいおんさんの曲でした。
Yes, that was a song by K-ON!
というわけで、このあとはね、あの、実はみんな衝撃の事実かもしれないんだけど、なんと！グッズが出るんですね！というわけで、宣伝担当の紫咲シオンさん、お願いします！
And now, after this... um, this might actually be shocking news to everyone, but guess what! Goods are coming out! So, Murasaki Shion in charge of promotions, please take it away!
にやってまいりましたー！
Everyone, I've finally arrived!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、
So, to celebrate,
活動4周年記念グッズがこの後22時から発売開始！
my 4th anniversary goods go on sale tonight at 22:00!
というわけで、めちゃまずもうね見てのと通りめちゃくちゃ可愛いこの
First of all, just as you can see,
イラストがね、
the illustration is...
イラストの時点で「え、可愛い！綺麗過ぎ美し過ぎ」っていうコメントが絶対流れてると思います。
I'm sure people are saying, "It's so cute!" and "It's gorgeous!"
（笑）
(Laughs)
はい、というわけでね、見ていきましょう、グッズの方を。
So let's check out the goods, okay?
はい、まず一つ目！
First up, item number one:
「塩っ子プルゾン」。
the "Shiokko Pullover."
これはですね、みんなに外で着てほしくて、
This is designed so you'll want to wear it outside,
外で着れるようなシンプルめなデザインをめちゃめちゃ一生懸命考えました。
and keeps a simple design you can wear outside.
めちゃ形とかにこだわって、色とかにもめちゃこだわったんですよ。
We really focused on the shape, the colors, and everything!
まずね、見ていきましょう。胸の刺繍デザイン、これね紫咲シオンの
Let's check it out. The chest embroidery design features Murasaki Shion's...
あのこのね、髪型の顔？顔ってか髪型がねあの付いて真ん中にSということで、
hair style, wait, hair style? Her hair is on it, with an "S" in the middle!
めちゃいい！めちゃいい！
It's so good! It's really good!
これが刺繍されて胸の部分につくわけなんですよ。
This is embroidered and placed right on the chest area.
めちゃいい。
It's so good!
ちなみにあの、サンプルの形もちゃんと似たんですけど、めちゃくちゃ良かった。
By the way, the sample shape was spot-on, and it turned out great!
で、裏にねタグ、タグ！グランドっぽい、紫咲シオンブランドみたいな感じでタグデザインが入ってますね。
And on the back, there's a tag... a grand-looking "Murasaki Shion Brand" tag design!
めちゃいいじゃん！紫咲シオンって書いてある。もうめちゃいい。
It says "Murasaki Shion." That's so good!
これをみんなに着てほしいんです。会社に行く時、
I really want everyone to wear this when you go to work,
ね、いつでももうどこでもいつでもどこでも身につけてお出かけする時にも身につけてってほしいなと思って、外に出れるようなデザインにしました。フリーサイズでできてます。
or anytime, anywhere, when you're going out—I want you to wear it. It comes in one free size!
ね、これ本当に着てマジでお願いいっしょうのお願い。
This is honestly something I'm begging you to wear—a once-in-a-lifetime plea.
うそ、一生に30回目ぐらいのお願い。
Well, like about 30 lifetimes' worth of requests!
次。
Next,
一緒にお出かけリバーシブルトートバッグ。
the "Let's Go Out Together Reversible Tote Bag."
めちゃ可愛い！これはね、あのキービジュアルの、あの最初にねでてきた画像イラストの
So cute! This is based on the initial Key Visual illustration...
えー、リバーシブルトートバッグということでね、
a reversible tote bag!
これめちゃいい！何がいいかっていうと、
This is so good! You know what makes it good?
まずイラストの部分が、イラストが全面に書いてある方の、えートートバッグのデザインと、
First, the illustration side features the full illustration on the front...
裏返したら、
and if you flip it over,
Bになって、この黒いね、黒い真っ黒のところにこのロゴ、紫咲シオン、シオンのロゴが入ってる。
it becomes side B, featuring a plain black background with the Murasaki Shion logo!
めちゃ可愛いよね、このロゴ。
Isn't this logo so cute?
めちゃ可愛い。だから、あのー、
So, you know...
ちょっと、あの今日はちょっと、あの、大事な、大事な用事、大事な用事の時に持って行ってください。
today is... well, it's for important occasions. Please bring it for important occasions!
今日は大事な用事だから、あのちょっとシンプルめのほうで行かないとって時はね、このBで。
Today is an important occasion, so if you want to keep it simple, use side B.
今日もシオンちゃんもう大好き過ぎてもう全面に押し出していこうって時はね、もうAでね、ぜひ持ち歩いてください。
And if you love Shion-chan so much that you want to show her off everywhere, use side A!
めちゃ可愛い！あのさっきのプルゾンと合わせて持ち運んでください！めちゃ可愛いもう、もうめちゃ可愛い大絶賛。
It's so cute—please carry this along with the pullover! It's so, so cute!
次。
Next,
ランダムラバーストラップ。
the "Random Rubber Strap."
はい、これもうねめちゃ可愛いよね！もうさ、可愛いしか言えないんだけど、だって可愛いのもしょうがないじゃんね！
Yes! This is also so cute, right? I can only say it's cute!
というわけでね、あの4種類からランダムに1種類入ってますよというわけで、
So, one of four types is included at random.
はい！これね、めちゃ可愛いよね！
Yes! This is so cute, right?
あのね、シオン的には一番右のやつが、もうめちゃ可愛い塩っ子ぎゅって抱いてて、
I'd say the one on the far right has Shion-chan squeezing a "Shiokko."
この塩っ子、なんかさ、塩っ子ってさリスナーなわけじゃん。ね、ちょっとなんかリスナーとぎゅってちょっと炎上しちゃいますよ（笑）。
People call them "Shiokko," so if we're "Shiokko" and she's "Gyutto," it's a bit... wait, is that going to cause a scandal? (Laughs)
めちゃ可愛いんだけど！
It's so cute, though!
シオン的にはこの右のやつが一番お勧めっていうか、可愛い。全部可愛いんだけど一番好きなんだよね。
Even though I said that, the one on the right is my favorite—well, I love all of them, but that one's my favorite.
あとね、このゴスロリシオンもねめちゃ可愛いね。
And the "Gosurori Shion" is also super cute.
全部可愛いな。全部手に入れてね、あのトートバッグにじゃらじゃらつけてほしいですね、あのー、
They're all so cute! I want you to get all of them and attach them all jangling to your tote bag.
はい。
Yes!
昔のね、ちょっと前のグッズでアクキーとかね缶バッチもあったから、そういうグッズをねいっぱいトートバッグにつけて持ち運んでほしいなという思いから、ランダムラバーストラップ、今回はラバーストラ、ラバーストラップになっております。
We had Akukin and badges with older goods, so I really wanted you to put lots of goods on your tote bag—that's why we made it a rubber strap this time!
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、なんと！なんと、ななんと！
And guess what—guess what, what, what!
フルセット購入特典、ほし先生描き下ろしポストカードに、数量限定で直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきます。
The full-set purchase bonus includes a Holsi-sensei illustrated postcard, plus a handwritten signature and printed message!
こちら数量限定なんですけど、めちゃくちゃ多いから、
It's quantity-limited, but there are so many!
めちゃくちゃ多いんだよ。めちゃ、あの頑張るつもりで、がんばる、がんばるつもりで、あの多くしたので、
There are so many, so I'm going to try my best—I'll really, really try my best to sign as many as I can.
あの、ぜひあの余らない、余らなかったら余らないようにたくさん皆さんあの、手に入れてください！紫咲シオンのサインを。あんまやんない、本当に久しぶりだってぐらい、結構久しぶりの
So please, so that there are no leftovers, make sure you all get your hands on Murasaki Shion's signature!
直筆サインなんですけど、
handwritten signature!
たぶんね、この先もね、あんまやる機会ないと思うから、ぜひここでばっちり手に入れてほしいですね。まあ数量限定なんだけど。
I probably won't have many chances to do this in the future, so I really want you to grab it here—well, it is quantity-limited, though.
はい！
Yes!
買えなかった人のようにも、フルセットで
Even for those who couldn't buy it, the full set
箔押しサイン&メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきます。
comes with a foil-signed & messaged postcard.
こっちはね、あの金で、金のいつもの箔押しになっていて、
This one features the usual gold foil stamping,
メッセージ何が入ってるかわからないよ、みたいな感じになっていると思います。
and I think it'll be like, "I wonder what message is inside!"
ぜひ、あのよろしくお願いします。
So please, I hope you'll check it out.
手に入れてください、絶対に。すべて、
Make sure to get your hands on it.
すべて身にまとってるところを推しは、見たいので、
I want to see you wearing all of it,
あのぜひ届いたら、あの全身の写真でもTwitterに載せてください、見たいです。
so please post full-body photos on Twitter when it arrives!
はい、以上の4点ですね。
Yep, so those are the 4 items.
あのポストカードも合わせて4点となっております。
Including the postcard, it makes 4 items in total.
こちらぜひ手に入れてくださいね、皆さん。
Please definitely get your hands on them, everyone!
はい、返事は？
Yes, what's your answer?
はい、ということでこの後22時からグッズの方もよろしくお願いします。
Right, so the merch sales start at 22:00 later.
チェックしてください。
Please check it out!
そして、なんとさらにもう一つ、重大告知がこのあとあるかも！
And what's more, there might be another big announcement coming up!
以上宣伝担当の紫咲シオンでしたー！
That's all from PR representative Murasaki Shion!
はい、ということで宣伝担当の紫咲シオンさんでしたーね、
Right, that was PR rep Murasaki Shion-san, wasn't it?
みんなグッズちゃんと見てた？
Did you guys properly check out the merch?
トートバッグとブルゾンとランダムラバーストラップと、
The tote bag, the blouson, the random rubber strap,
あとね特番で、あの数量限定で直筆サイン入りポストカード、
and the special stream's limited hand-signed postcard...
えーっと、数量限定じゃないほうが、あの、複製のね、メッセージが入ってるポストカードです。
Um, for the non-limited version, it's a postcard with a printed message.
えー、みんなにね、ブルゾンを着てほしくてね、頑張って考えました。
Um, I really wanted you all to wear the blouson, so I worked hard on it.
あの、デザインとかね。デザインにどうしようみたいなやつとかね。
Thinking about the design and what it should look like.
考えとかってみんな着てね、あれ、あれ着て、中に半袖Tシャツ着て出かけるんだよ。
I thought, everyone should wear it, put on a short-sleeve T-shirt inside, and go out.
あれでみんなは仕事に行くのこれから毎日。分かった？
That's what you'll wear to work every day from now on. Got it?
ね、可愛いでしょ？であとトートバッグもね、
Right, isn't it cute? And the tote bag too...
トートバッグにぎりしめて着て、ラバーストラップをトートバッグに
You clutch the tote bag, attach lots of rubber straps to it,
じゃらじゃらいっぱいつけて、お仕事行くか、ねみんな、これから。
and head off to work, everyone, from now on!
頑張ってね、お仕事。はい、ということで皆さんぜひグッズの方もね、チェックしてください。
Do your best at work! Anyway, please make sure to check out the merch, everyone.
で、ここで紫咲シオンから、非常に残念、残念じゃねえわ、非常に大事な、大事な
And now, from Murasaki Shion, a very unfortunate... unfortunate? No, a very, very important
重大告知があります。
major announcement!
このあと、なんとKanariaさん書き下ろしの新曲オリジナル曲「シャンデリア」歌います！
Starting right now, I'll be singing my new original song "Chandelier" written by Kanaria!
びっくりしたっしょ？みんな。
Were you surprised, everyone?
それでは、ぜひ聴いてください、「シャンデリア」。
Now then, please listen to "Chandelier".
叶わない叶わないのネタミソウ行き場のない情熱と苦しさを
Unfulfillable, unfulfillable jealousy, the passion and suffering with nowhere to go
神様から貰ってシャラララララララ衝動からは逆らえないわ
Received from God, shallalalala, you cannot resist the impulse
あとちょっとそっとずっとずっと秘密ごとは譲れないわかなわないわ
A little more, softly, always, always, I won't yield my secrets, it won't come true
あとちょっとの距離イメージ秘密ごとは語らないわ忘れないわ
Just a little closer distance, image, I won't talk about my secrets, I won't forget
まだまだ抱きしめきってハッピーだったらだらくもきってマイウェイからいつなんざってまたいつなんねお願いぎゅっとハグして
Hugging tight, if happy then slothful, from my way, whenever, whenever again, please hug me tight
抱きしめきってハッピーはたまたまくもきってマイウェイならお願い聞いて頭がいいんでしょ
Hugging tight, happy, or perhaps letting go from my way, please listen, you're smart, right?
叶わない叶わないのネタミソウ行き場のない情熱と痛みをも
Unfulfillable, unfulfillable jealousy, even the passion and pain with nowhere to go
神様から貰ってシャラララララララ衝動からは逃げられないわ
Received from God, shallalalala, you can't run away from the impulse
抱きしめきってハッピーだったらだらくもきってマイウェイからいつなんざってまたいつなんねお願いぎゅっとハグして
Hugging tight, if happy then slothful, from my way, whenever, whenever again, please hug me tight
ハッピーハッピーハッピーばたばた前を向けシャララウェイならいつなんざってまたいつなんねお願いぎゅっとラブリィな
Happy happy happy, flap flap face forward, shalla-way, whenever, whenever again, please a lovely...
ラッキー残金ハッピーまだまだあいまいあいあいあいあいにお願い聞いて叶えはずかしいでしょ
Lucky balance, happy, still ambiguous, ai ai ai ai, please listen and make it embarrassing, right?
叶わない叶わないのネタミソウ行き場のない情熱と痛みをも
Unfulfillable, unfulfillable jealousy, even the passion and pain with nowhere to go
神様から貰ってシャラララララララ衝動からは逆らえないわ
Received from God, shallalalala, you cannot resist the impulse
心の底まで近づいてまだ挨拶する恋はするぜタイア心の底まで二人で近づいてほら衝動からは逆らえないわ
Approaching to the heart's core, still saying hello, love will tie, approaching together to the core, look, you cannot resist the impulse
はーい！
Hi there!
というわけで「シャンデリア」どうだったでしょうか？
So, what did you think of "Chandelier"?
このあとすぐ22時から「シャンデリア」のMVがプレミア公開されます！
Right after this at 10:00 PM, the "Chandelier" music video will premiere!
22時からですよう！このあとすぐですよ！
Starting at 10:00 PM! Right after this!
ぜひ見てくださいね、ぜーんいん！
Make sure to check it out, everyone!